Jordan Doczy

1305 Hathaway Rd. Dayton, OH 45419 hello@jordandoczy.com 303.478.6471

Summary

A digital professional with over 14 years of experience in roles ranging from Lead Developer to Executive Producer. My passion for technology and digital applications has led me to focus on a career in mobile development. Along with several years of development experience I bring a firm understanding of project-lifecycle, SCRUM/AGILE methodologies, Design-Thinking, and best practices.

Portfolio: jordandoczy.com

Github: github.com/jordandoczy

Apple: itunes.apple.com/us/developer/jordan-doczy/id1062387752

Experience

iOS Application Developer, Krush Technologies

Dayton, OH — April 2016 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Develop, deploy, and maintain iOS applications
- Provide estimates for feature development
- Design and architect solutions for key features
- Lead developer for the *Flinch* application (https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/flinch-video-chat-staring-contest/id862550306?mt=8)
- Sr. Developer for the ooVoo application (https://itunes.apple.com/us/developer/oovoo-llc/id422303841?mt=8)

iOS Application Developer, Freelance

San Francisco, CA - 2015 - 2016

Published Apps:

- Tetra Fire (https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tetra-fire/id1085398276?mt=8)
- MatchPop! (https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/matchpop/id1062419829?mt=8)
- instanote (https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/insta-note/id1067575526?mt=8)

Executive Producer, Odopod

San Francisco, CA - 2012 - 2015

Responsibilities:

- Oversee the producer group (5 producers)
- Write and review detailed SOWs
- Produce detailed project plans (estimates, schedules, resourcing)
- Gather and produce business requirements, technical and functional specifications
- Manage project budgets from \$1 \$3 million
- Manage a team of strategists, copywriters, interaction designers, visual designers, developers, and QA resources

Sr. Technical Producer, Crispin Porter + Bogusky

Boulder, CO − *2011 - 2012*

Responsibilities:

- Managed project budgets from \$200k \$1.5 million for American Express
- Managed a team of producers, developers, analysts, and creative resources
- Lead technical communications for external agencies
- Promoted use of AGILE/SCRUM process across all domains
- Gathered and produced business requirements, technical and functional specifications

Lead Developer, 180 Amsterdam

Amsterdam, The Netherlands — 2010 - 2011

Responsibilities:

- Led the redesign of the adidas global sports performance web site
- Led multiple projects for the 2010 adidas World Cup campaign
- Consultant for new creative/technical briefs
- Provided proof of concepts and case studies for creative/technical briefs
- Lead technical communications for external/offshore agencies
- Lead architect for Flash solutions

Sr. Flash Developer, Critical Mass

Chicago, IL - 2007 - 2009

Responsibilities:

- Lead Flash developer for the Chicago office
- Performance manager for junior Flash developers
- Project estimation/scoping

Sr. Web Developer, JMDoczy Solutions

Dayton, OH − *2006* - *2007*

Responsibilities:

- Independent Web Developer (Flash, .Net, HTML)
- Consultant for creative/technical briefs

Web Developer, Resource Interactive

Columbus, OH - 2003 - 2006

Responsibilities:

- Developer (HTML, PHP, Flash, .Net)
- Lead Flash developer for Scotts, Wexner Center for the Arts, and New York and Co.
- Web developer on HP account

Education

The Ohio State University

Columbus, OH — 1999 - 2003

- B.A. Interactive Communication Processes
- Minor Computer Information Sciences

MIT

Online — 2017 Q2

• Completion of 6.00.2x: Introduction to Computational Thinking and Data Science

Skills

iOS Development, Object Oriented Programming, Design Patterns, Quality Assurance, Release Management, AGILE / SCRUM Processes, Waterfall Process, Project Management, Planning, Budget Tracking, Performance Management, Technical Consulting, Strategic Oversight, JIRA, Postman

Languages

Swift 3.0, Objective-C, C++, Java, Kotlin, HTML, CSS, JS, AngularJS, BootStrap, PhP, C#, Django, MySQL